<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Payground</string>
    <string name="sample_text">The Contet laboratory investigates the genetic determinants and molecular mechanisms driving excessive alcohol drinking. A first aspect of our research focuses on known molecular targets of alcohol, such as GIRK and BK channels, two potassium channels that can be activated by alcohol in vitro. Our goal is to assess the in vivo relevance of alcohol's action on these proteins by evaluating their contribution to acute intoxication, tolerance, voluntary drinking and dependence. A second aspect of our research explores the neurocircuitry mediating the role of the neuropeptide CRF in the transition to alcohol dependence and in the symptomatology of alcohol withdrawal. This work involves a combination of histological, electrophysiological and behavioral studies. Finally, we are undertaking exploratory projects, which aim to identify novel genes contributing to or protecting from excessive drinking.

To achieve these goals, we use validated mouse models of differential alcohol intake, in combination with a variety of genetic tools, such as knockout and transgenic mice, as well as viral vectors. We have recently established mouse models of intravenous cocaine and heroin self-administration and anticipate extending the same approaches used for alcohol to uncover common and distinct determinants of addiction to these substances. We are also providing other investigators with validated tools to manipulate gene expression in rodents through TSRI Alcohol Research Center Viral Vector Core.

Ultimately, our hope is to curb the devastating impact of alcoholism and drug addiction on individuals, their family and the community as a whole, through the identification of vulnerable populations and the development of better treatments. If you share our dedication to this goal, you can help our research by making a donation to the Pearson Center. Your support will make a difference.</string>
</resources>
